Curriculum Vitae Eyasin Arafat

PERSONAL INFORMATION

MD. EYASIN ARAFAT



70/SHEROIL COLONY, POST: GHORAMARA (6100), THANA: BOALIA, DISTRICT: RAJSHAHI.

■ +8801723105974

x arafat082048@gmail.com,

Sex Male | Date of birth 04/09/1989 | Nationality Bangladeshi Marital Status: Married.

Career Summary

A professionally driven Mechanical Engineer with more than four years of work experience who will provide business development, optimum project engineering design, troubleshooting, fire hydrant design, infrastructure construction monitoring and inspection as well as project development plan review and approval.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/01/2015-21/12/2017

Assistant Manager (Industrial)

Ejab distribution Ltd. a sole distributor of Cepsa Lubricant, Spain.

- Take care of Diesel and Gas power plant services (such as lube oil testing report from origin (Spain), analysing the testing report and gives guidelines as a recommendation and maintain liaison with the origin.
- Investigate equipment failures and difficulties to diagnose faulty operation of powerplant and take necessary action.
- Develop and deploy quality training with proper materials / presentations for all sales and service personnel to provide customer better service and making awareness.
- Develop plan to maximize personnel productivity and making quarterly basis performance appraisal individually.

03/01/2014-31/12/2014

Project Engineer (Mechanical)

Aim tech Ltd. (Fire & safety Department)

- Design of Pump Hydration System, Friction loss and hydraulic calculation.
- Collaborate with electrical engineers and other personnel to identify, define, and solve departmental problems.
- Assist superior to execute and evaluate workers performance, motivating workers, Incentive planning, disciplinary matters, and training needs.
- Provide support to the project by maintaining a visible presence to the field performing site visits to the entire
 project and conduct formal weekly job site inspections.
- Making project Quotation, Client Handling and Estimate the project Materials.
- Directing and leading the core team of technical personnel.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2018-2020 MS in Mechanical Engineering

King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals (KFUPM)

- Knowledge acquired: Mechanical behaviour of material, Finite Element method for mechanical engineers Continuum Mechanics, Advance dynamics, Noise and Vibration control, Sustainable Design and development (LCA through Simapro software), Corrosion in Petrochemical Industry etc.
- Cgpa = 3.375 in the score of 4.00

2009-2013 B. Sc.in Mechanical Engineering

Rajshahi University of Engineering and Technology (RUET)

- Knowledge acquired: Automobile Engineering, Fluid mechanics (turbulent and laminar flows, diffusion, and transport equation etc.), Internal combustion engine (reason of detonation and minimization process, gas-turbine engine performance), thermodynamics (exergy, exergy balance), Power plant (types of powerplant, working procedure)
- Cgpa = 3.43 in the score of 4.00

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)
Other language

Bangla		
UNDERSTANDING	SPEAKING	WRITING

Curriculum Vitae Eyasin Arafat

Listening Reading Spoken interaction Spoken production

English C2 C2 C2 C1 C2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

Communication skills

Very good communication skill in English, gained through my experience as a graduate student in a foreign university.

HVAC design Basics

SM TECHNO MEP & NLP TRAINING SERVICES, India (online) Nov'2020 to Dec'2020 2 months

Computer Skill

- Software's: ANSYS (CFD, Workbench), ABAQUS, Solid Work, AUTOCAD, MATLAB (Optimization using GA, PSO), Python Basic, C/C++, Machine learning basic, and Mathematica.
- Microsoft Office: Microsoft Office Program

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Publications

- Eyasin Arafat, Fadi A. Al-Badour, and Necar Merah, "Fully Coupled Thermo-Mechanical Finite Element Modelling of Friction Stir Processing of Super Duplex Stainless Steel". (Accepted to International Journal of Advanced Manufacturing Technology, 2020)
- Eyasin Arafat Necar Merah, Fadi A. Al-Badour "Fatigue Crack Growth Behavior of Friction Stir Processed Super Duplex Stainless Steels (SAF- 2507)". Materials Today Communications (26) 2021 101937. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2020.101937
- A. Helal, M. E. Arafat, M. M. Rahman, Pyridinyl Conjugate of UiO-66-NH2 as Chemosensor for the Sequential Detection of Iron and Pyrophosphate Ion in Aqueous Media, Chemosensors (8) 2020 122. doi:10.3390/chemosensors8040122
- 4. M M Rahman, M H Zahir M. E. Arafat, M A J Mazumder, R Suleiman, and A. M Kumar, "UV-shielding by a polyurethane/f-Oil fly ash-CeO2 protective coating," Int. J. appl. Polym. sci., 2020. https://doi.org/10.1002/app.49904.
- 5. Helal, M. Usman, M. E. Arafat, and M. M. Abdelnaby, "Allyl Functionalized UiO-66 Metal-Organic Framework as a Catalyst for the Synthesis of Cyclic Carbonates by CO2 Cycloaddition," J. Ind. Eng. Chem., 2020, doi:10.1016/j.jiec.2020.05.016.
- M. M. Rahman, M. H. Zahir, M. B. Haq, A. Madhan Kumar, M. E. Arafat, and M. M. Rabbani, "Silicone-enriched surface of immersed polyurethane-POSS antifouling coating," Int. J. Polym. Anal. Charact., vol. 25, no. 5, pp. 385–395, 2020, doi: 10.1080/1023666X.2020.1796106.
- Helal, Aasif; Cordova, Kyle; Arafat, Md. Eyasin; Usman, Muhammad; Yamani, Zain,"Defect-Engineering a Metal-Organic Framework for CO2 Fixation in the Synthesis of Bioactive Oxazolidinone,"Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers, 2020.https://doi.org/10.1039/D0QI00496K
- 8. Md. Shamim Akhter, Abul Hasanat and Md. Eyasin Arafat (2013). Bahera (T. Bellirica) Biodiesel Production in Bangladesh, Characterization of Bahera Biodiesel and its Performance on a Diesel Engine, volume 13, Global Journals Inc. (USA), ISSN:0975-5861

Conference paper

- Submitted paper
- 9. S.D. Nath and **Md. Eyasin Arafat** "Generation of hydrogen from biomass through Thermo-chemical fluidized bed gasification." 3rd ICMIME **2017**, RUET, Rajshahi, Bangladesh.
- 10. Md. Eyasin Arafat, Azazul Haque, Chadni Pervin, and M.M Rahman, Downhole corrosion challenges and mitigation." (submitted to Corrosion Engineering Science and Technology).

Honours and awards

- Deanship Graduate Scholarship (2018-2020) | Awarded by King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals.
- Champion of Mechanical Design Expo 2018 | Awarded by King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals.
- Outstanding player Award | Cricket tournament | RUET (2013)
- Technical Scholarship | Academic good standing | RUET (2010-2013)

References:

Dr. Fadi Al-Badour Associate Professor, DEPT.OF ME (KFUPM)

Email: fbadour@kfupm.edu.sa Mobile: +966-13-860 8399 Dr. Aasif helal Research Scientist II, CENTER OF RESEARCH EXCELLENCE IN NANO-TECHNOLOGY, KFUPM.

Email: aasifh@kfupm.edu.sa Mobile: +966536825719